[music]
All right, questions.
>> Um, James Olstre came back to practice
last week, then missed the next two
estimation days. I'm just curious, did
he have a a setback or is it still a
situation where we hope to get him back?
>> No, that was that was normal what we
were doing. That's what we wanted to do
last week. Uh, so he didn't he didn't
miss any time. He was uh you know it was
kind of how we had it planned. So he was
out there walked through. We're going to
have him out at practice today and um
you know there again would love to have
him at the game. Uh barring no setback.
We'll see see where he goes here.
>> What's the plan to still uh get
Christian rolling back into practice and
and um what's the likelihood that that
he could, you know, still help you this
year?
>> Uh yeah, I mean we're going to work him
into practice. You know, this will uh
start working him working him in. Um,
and yeah, I mean, I'm I'm hopeful that
we'll be able to get him at some point
here this season.
>> Mohamd was defensive player of the week
this week. You know, he had the three
sacks. Looked like you guys used him a
little bit more on the edge for some of
those. He was getting some of his
production inside early on. Was that a
game plan specific thing? Is there
something about um, you know, what he
can do for you out there that you want
to get him rushing more? Yeah, I mean
it's just putting our best rushers out
there and and uh he's one of those guys
and um so you know we felt like getting
him on the edge opposite of Hutch on
some stuff. Um he had some early
production too so you're just going to
keep going back to the well there. Um
but you know he did a great job. He does
a good job for us no matter what. I mean
he's playing special teams for us too
now. he's, you know, he's running on
kickoffs and I mean, he he does anything
you ask him to do and, uh, you know, he
cares about it and he works at it and
whatever you need, he'll do. So, um, you
know, proud of him, man. He helped us
win that game the other day.
>> What have you thought about Davenport's
performance since he's been back? I'm
sure there was probably at least a
little rust he needed to knock off.
>> Yeah, I I mean, there's um I I would say
that's probably the best way to say it
is just, you know, getting his legs back
under him here a little bit, you know.
Um the good news is that we've every
week we've gotten a few more reps on
him. You know, he's getting some really
good reps. Um practice, you know, he he
he looks really good in practice. Um you
know, he's very disruptive and uh and so
um he's only going to get better from
from the what he's had the last couple
of weeks, the last three weeks of
practice or, you know, few days that
we've had. So, um so this will be good
for him.
>> I'm glad we got him back. with with
Miles. Uh does it speak to any about him
and how quickly he's you know kind of
catching on the fact that he just
returned to practice about a month ago
when you already feel comfortable
putting him into games? Nate kind of did
the same thing with Christian last year,
but is that still a little bit unusual
for him to
>> uh I think it's unusual. You know, I
think that's it's not always easy to do.
Um you know, especially that's it's hard
especially when you're in the boat that
they're in when you don't get any
training camp and you've only gotten
limited practices. I mean, that's that's
not uh it's not easy to do, but you
know, it's where we're at. You know, we
we need to get a look and we need a
little help and um and so, you know,
let's let's throw him out there and uh
you know, he he got some valuable
experience and he's going to learn and
grow from it. He'll be better because of
it. Um so, that's a good thing.
>> Given the situation that you have at
tight end, what kind of lift does Jir
give in the passing game? You mean just,
you know, being able to line him up in
different positions, uh, including the
slot?
>> Well, he's an asset. You know, he's he's
a weapon for us. You know, we've said
that all along. And this guy does, uh,
serves many roles and, uh, he gives us a
lot of flexibility. Um, you know, with
with what we can do. So, um, you know,
I've said this before, the more that we
ask him to do, the better he gets and
the more he can do, you know. Um, but he
he allows us to do a lot. So, um, you
know, he's a good player. He's a good
player and he's only getting better.
>> Last week, [clears throat] you, um, you
played an opponent had maybe a rare
situation where they had two elite
receivers you had to shut down,
>> another one this week with with Adams
and Nua. [clears throat] I'm just
curious what what did you take away from
last week's performance that can apply
to this, or is there nothing because
they're so different stylistically?
>> Well, I think they're they're a little
different just in style of play. um you
know overall yet uh you know Piggin is a
physical receiver. He's big. He's long
and uh so is Nua. You know he's a big
guy. And uh you know Nikua you you can't
you know I got a lot of respect for him.
Uh just particularly over the last two
years since we played him. When you get
to see the guy up close and go against
him you realize how big and strong he
is. you know, uh he's got good range. Um
he's faster than I think people realize.
I mean, he runs well, you know, and then
he blocks, you know, I mean, he gets
after it. So, um so you got to fight
this guy all the way to the catch point.
And so what you learn from last week is
really what we did. I thought we fought
on the perimeter, you know. I thought
Rock and Amique and those guys really
fought, man. Reed, um particularly
against three, you had to, you know, and
we're going to have to do that again
against 12. He's a really good player,
man. He's stout. strong. And then
obviously Adams is, man, he's kind of
slithery. He's smooth. Um, you know, and
and you you got to be careful on the
double moves. He he does a real good job
with his stems and dropping his weight.
And so there's a you know, he's he's
there's some he's pretty elegant with
his routes, man. You got to be careful.
Um cuz he he'll he'll make you bite on
something and uh and then he's gone the
other way. So, they are different in
that regard, but they're both very
dangerous receivers.
>> With the tight end room being revamped,
what do you like so far about having uh
Fergie and uh Richie on on the roster?
>> Well, um the the Roocci and Richie
brothers just got here.
So, I don't know a ton. Um but but just
for the short period of time here, you
know, they're they're good, you know,
and and we'll see where we can go with
them, you know. Um, obviously FK, I got
a lot of trust in FK was here before. I
know what he is. We know what he is.
He's a smart guy. He's pretty crafty,
savvy in the pass game. Uh, can do a lot
of different jobs and so can Zilstra,
right? So, uh, we know what those guys
kind of deliver. And then, you know,
Skip is our kind of de facto tight end,
too, that we use. So, we'll see where
the other two guys um where they can go
or where they can help and how they can
grow. But, but, uh, got a lot of a lot
of trust in FK. Um, and and Shane,
>> sorry, Dan. Hutch said last week that
you guys took the reins off the D line a
bit just to create more and and to rush
with more of a pass first mentality even
when it might be a run. Just how much
credit goes to your linebackers, maybe
Jack in particular for allowing you guys
to rush more aggressively and to put out
fires against the run if they need to?
>> Well, yeah. I mean there's there's a lot
said we put a we put an enormous amount
of strain on those three guys on you
know Jack particular they're in the
middle but Alex as well and then even
Barnes. So um but those guys do we we
asked them to do a lot and uh um and
they do a million jobs for us. Um and it
was really look it was good job by by
Shep. It was good job by Casey too our
Dline coach you know that was a lot of
that was hey man this is this is what we
need to do against this opponent. this
is how we can help ourselves depending
on what the play is or or the situation
is. But there's no doubt if you don't
have the backers we have, you can't do
that. U because you'll be in trouble,
you know, you you'll get gutted for for
a lot of runs, uh a lot of yards inside,
which we were able to uh minimize, you
know, especially in a light box.
>> Uh when you when you look at Jack in
particular, you're starting to see
things, you know, first linebacker since
Chris Spielman to do this or whatever.
Just just overall, Dan, how valuable is
Jack in in what you do from a game
preparation standpoint and then
obviously what he means to you in the
middle of that defense on Sunday?
>> Well, I mean, I don't know if you can
put it into words. You know, he's uh
he's extremely valuable. You know, right
now he first of all, he leads the team
in amount of reps that he's played for a
season. Um he he's he's taken more reps
than anybody on this team. He plays on
kickoff for us. uh and he's uh he's an
asset on kickoff and then everything you
see on defense. He doesn't come off the
field. He's our bellcow green dot. Um
and and he does and the guy is he's
smart and he's instinctive and he is uh
snap the whistle all out all the time in
practice too. He doesn't take plays off,
he doesn't take days off. He goes after
the football. He's a ball guy. So uh
he's invaluable. You talk a lot about
your your coaching influences in your
past. What do you see about the way that
that Brad brought things from LA and
that Rams organization that that's
helped you build here and are there any
similarities in the organizations that
you see mirrored because of of his
upbringing within that organization?
>> Well, I think you're always going to
take bits and pieces of what where you
kind of learned and grew under and and
those thoughts. And I just think uh you
know, they've always done a good job of
drafting. You know, they draft football
players, they find guys uh and they go
get their guys. And I I think that's a
lot of what we do here too, you know,
and yeah, I think that would be a better
question for Brad, but certainly there's
there's you can't argue with what
they've done uh with the players they've
drafted. They got some really good
players in all rounds uh and free agency
um like we have. So, um you know, and
that's kind of the tree he's from. So,
certainly you're going to have a little
influence from it.
>> Dan back players he drafted was was uh
Verse. I just want to get your
impressions on what sort of game record
he is. And when when Verse was was
sliding a little bit in that draft, he
was getting kind of close to where you
guys were. Did you think you might be
able to get him at some point that
>> We like Verse. He's a good player. He's
a really good player and he's grown so
much in a year. I mean, this guy is uh
he is he he's a violent player. Um and
he can he can wreck a game. Um I mean,
he's he this guy sets violent edges uh
in the run game and then he gets an
edge, it's over. those guys collectively
do a good job running stunts and pick
games, things things like that. Um, he
he's man, he's really grown. But, um,
you know, but yeah, we liked him, you
know, we liked him.
>> Dan, back to Jack real fast. He seems
like kind of a throwback offball
linebacker. Does he remind you of anyone
that you played with or against during
your playing days? man, he's um you
know, he's
I that it's a good question. Um I mean,
look, there's there's I wouldn't say um
you know, played with, but but you know,
some of these guys when you see um just
being at New Orleans as a coach for that
period of time and watching Keequley out
there, you know, now Keequley for
linebacker had rare speed. Um, but as
far as all the other stuff, man, I there
there was a lot of similarities.
Freaking smart, man. He knows what's
coming before it's there. Um, high
energy, never gets tired. Freaking runs
all the way down the field, runs back to
the huddle, gets everybody lined up.
He's constantly barking out,
communication, going after the football.
You may get him once, you're not going
to get him twice. So, there's those
those things that just, you know, they
show up. They show up. Curious really
quickly, um Brian Branch, um has he
undergone surgery? Does swelling have to
go down before that happens? And when
when do you think maybe you'll have an
early sense of, you know, how long the
the recovery is for this given the maybe
advancements of
>> Yeah.
>> He has he's had it repaired. Uh and it
sounds like everything went well. So,
you know, they're always going to give
you the whatever 8 to 12 months or
whatever that is from from the time of
the surgery. But every the surgery went
well. Everything went well. Good job,
guys. Appreciate it. Yep. Thanks.
[music]